so let's see if we understood the
coherence definition
let's say that we have two cores in a
system that is supposed to be coherent
let's say that core one executes this
program
it sets a to one
then waits for a to change from 1 so
it's going to loop here as long as a is
equal to 1 sets a again to 1 and then
prints done 1. at the same time when
core 1 is started on this
core 2 starts on another program that
writes 0 to the same location a
in shared memory waits until a changes
from 0
sets a to 0 again
then prints down 2 and remember that
core one and core two
need not necessarily execute these two
programs in lock steps so it's not
necessary that core one executes this
while core two does this core one does
this while core to this and so on it
could be for example that core runs
executes several of these while core 2
is still
not even beginning
so you can insert arbitrary delays in
between any of the statements here and
here the question for you is which of
the following printouts are possible
first core one prints done one then core
two prints down two
the next possibility first core two
prints down two then core one prints
done one the next option core one prints
down one
but core two
gets stuck and never gets to print done
two
the next option
is score one gets stuck and never gets
to print down one but core two
successfully prints done too
and the final option
is that nothing is printed because both
of the cores get stuck so neither of
them prints anything ever so which of
these five
options
are actually possible
when these two programs
run in a coherent system